Snow on the ground, but the ground's still red
Another young soldier taken, another mother's dread
From the 6 blocks to the 905 ends
This the life we live, where the strong survive, my friend
No peace in the winter, just a war that we wage
On the dangerous streets of the Great North Stage
Came up in the rap, where the winners are cruel
Frozen wasteland, but we playin' by the rules of the street
Timmy's cups in the cup holder, glizzy on my lap
Cruisin' through the junction, duckin' 5-0's tap
My youngin from the Rex, he ain't knowin' 'bout the pain
First time he caught a body, cried in the pourin' rain
Now he's cold like the ice on the sidewalk
His heart frozen solid, another soldier for the war talk
We trappin' out of town, now it's not a project in sight
But the struggle's still the same when you're fightin' for the light
Snow on the ground, but the ground's still red
Another young soldier taken, another mother's dread
From the 6 blocks to the 905 ends
This the life we live, where the strong survive, my friend
No peace in the winter, just a war that we wage
On the dangerous streets of the Great North Stage
My brother's in the max over in Collins Bay
Caught a body in Scarborough, now he's doin' life pay
He was trappin' out a Civic, tryna make a better way
Now his world a cell, dreamin' of a brighter day
But the streets don't love you, they just spit you right out
Make you tough, make you hard, fill your mind with nothin' but doubt
Remember Guernsey Day, purple and the blue
Now the only colors represent are the ones we stay true
It's a full-time job duckin' the heat from the law
And the opps in the 6, they just wanna see you fall
I move like a ghost in the city, never leave a trace
Got a youngin on the corner with a serious face
He's got a blicky in his waist, 4K on the dash
If the wrong car pull up, it's about to get gassed
No mask in the summer, you can see the hate in they eyes
They just lookin' for a reason for a body to rise
It's a chess move, man, gotta think ahead
'Cause when the laughter stops, it's the tears that are shed
I seen 'em drop my cousin right there on the Danforth
Now the only thing I feel is this thirstin' for a
Snow on the ground, but the ground's still red
Another young soldier taken, another mother's dread
From the 6 blocks to the 905 ends
This the life we live, where the strong survive, my friend
No peace in the winter, just a war that we wage
On the dangerous streets of the Great North Stage
They say Canada's peaceful, they don't know about the nights
When the only light you see is from the muzzle flashes bright
Out here in the suburbs, it's a different kind of trap
Spillin' lean in the basement, got the music goin' mad
My youngin from the 6, he's a product of the stress
Dropped out of school early, now he's dealin' with a mess
His mama's workin' doubles just to keep the lights on
While he's out here in the trenches 'til the break of dawn
It's a cycle that continues like the endless fallin' snow
A story of survival that the quiet North don't know
So I'm writin' these bars from the heart of the cold
A story that's tragic, a story that's told
By the kids in the region, the kids in the Jane
Who fightin' for respect, tryna break from the chain
I see the pain in their eyes, it's the same as my own
A generation lost with a heart made of stone
But we rise from the ashes in this frozen expanse
We take our shots, we take our chances
For the brothers up north who are grindin' in the freeze
This is more than just music, this is life's hard DC
Snow on the ground, but the ground's still red
Another young soldier taken, another mother's dread
From the 6 blocks to the 905 ends
This the life we live, where the strong survive, my friend
No peace in the winter, just a war that we wage
On the dangerous streets of the Great North Stage